Guide to the Stanford Arts Institute Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Arts Institute records
2007-2012
SC1013
Stanford Arts Institute.
Stanford University. Stanford Arts Initiative.
645120 megabyte(s)
The materials consist of digital photographs and videos documenting art performances developed or sponsored by the Stanford Institute for Creativity and the Arts (SiCa). Also included are annual reports, press materials and a copy of the SiCa website.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
The materials were transferred from the Stanford Institute for Creativity and the Arts, 2010.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Please contact Public Services (e-mail: speccollref@stanford.edu) for information on accessing these digital objects.
Biographical/Historical note
The Stanford Institute for Creativity and the Arts (SiCa), established in 2006 as part of the Stanford Arts Initiative, leads the development of new undergraduate arts programs; hosts artists in residence; administers new multidisciplinary graduate degree programs; awards grants for multidisciplinary arts research and teaching; incubates collaborative performances and exhibitions with campus partners and other institutions; and provides centralized communication for Stanford arts events and programs.
With the successful close of the Stanford Arts Initiative as part of the Stanford Challenge in 2012, the Stanford Institute for Creativity and the Arts (SiCa) became the Stanford Arts Institute. The Stanford Arts Institute focuses on promoting cross-disciplinary approaches to the arts—in teaching, research, and art-making.
Scope and Contents note
The materials consist of digital photographs and videos documenting art performances developed or sponsored by the Stanford Institute for Creativity and the Arts (SiCa). Also included are press materials, annual reports, and a copy of the SiCa website.
Arrangement note
The materials are arranged in five series: 1. Annual Reports; 2. Photographs; 3. Press; 4. Videorecordings and Gallery Files; 5. Website.
Access Terms
Arts.; Performing arts.
Collection Contents
- Annual reports, 2008-2010; Series 1
  - 2008-2009, 1 computer file(s) (PDF)
  - 2009-2010, 1 computer file(s) (PDF); 1 computer file (MHTML)
- Photographs, 2007-2010; Series 2; 193 gigabyte(s) (15770 computer files)
  - 2007
    - ShakeGirl
    - SLOrk
  - 2008
    - PAMF 2008 (Enrique Aguirre), 2008.04.24
    - RedRover (toni), 2008.05.28
    - China Tour (toni), 2008.06
    - PlaySound, 2008.07.08
    - Stanford Summer Theater, 2008.07
    - NSO Mural Making 2008 (bria), 2008.09.20
    - POTE08 (megan), 2008.10.02
    - Curtains exhibit (Toni), 2008.10.11
    - SiCaPresents Lunch (ben), 2008.10.14
    - Todd Reynolds (toni), 2008.10.15
    - Ceramics studio open house (megan), 2008.10.17
    - Grad Student Reception, 2008.10.22
    - Stanford Night at the de Young (greg james), 2008.11.07
    - Gaieties 2009 (Alex), 2008.11.19
    - Jan Estep Talk (Alvin), 2008.11.20
    - Mix (Alex), 2008.11.20
    - Martin Matalon (Alvin), 2008.12.05
    - Artist Show and Tell
  - 2009
    - Robert Perillo Workshop (Alvin), 2009.01.11
    - Yoko Ono (Toni), 2009.01.14
    - Vice Acoustic CoHo (Alex), 2009.01.15
    - Reactions to the Record II panel (ben), 2009.01.16
    - Reactions to the Record II - Rex Lawson (Alex), 2009.01.17
    - STREB - Crash Rehearsal (LA Cicero - Stanford News Service), 2009.01.21
    - STREB - Modern Dance Lecture (Alex), 2009.01.22
    - The Wiz (Alex), 2009.01.25
    - DJ SoCalled (Alvin), 2009.01.27
    - David Mamet (Alvin), 2009.01.28
    - PAMF 2009 (Enrique Aguirre), 2009.02.14
    - Rokia Traore Workshop (Alvin), 2009.02.03
    - Yoko Tawada, 2009.02.04
    - Mike Block Workshop (Alvin), 2009.02.18
    - Cantor MIX MikeBlock (Alvin), 2009.02.19
    - Love's Labour's Lost Rehearsal (Alvin), 2009.02.21
    - Jimmy Cobb (alex), 2009.02.23
    - Esperanza Spalding songwriters workshop (alex), 2009.02.26
    - Paul Dresher - artist show and tell (MARY), 2009.03.06
    - Graphic Novel Class (Alvin), 2009.03.09
    - Creative Writing Reading (Alex), 2009.03.10
    - desived_theater (Alex), 2009.03.13
    - dSchool Tour (megan), 2009.03.20
    - ME203 class presentations (megan), 2009.03.20
    - Lila Downs - songwriters, 2009.03.31
    - Art and Acoustics (Alvin), 2009.04.08
    - Guzheng and Chinese music rehearsal (megan), 2009.04.08
    - David Harrington (Alvin), 2009.04.09
    - Politics and the Novel (Alvin), 2009.04.10
    - AAA 09 (Megan), 2009.04.16
    - Art Affair Reception (Alvin), 2009.04.16
    - An Art Affair (Jason Chuang), 2009.04.17
    - AnArtAffair (Jianfeng Lin), 2009.04.17
    - Art Affair Day Two (Alvin), 2009.04.17
    - Art Affair Day Three (Alvin), 2009.04.18
    - Grafitti at AAA09 (News Service), 2009.04.18
    - Music and the Brain Symposium Day Two (Alvin), 2009.04.18
    - Rising Tide Conference (Alvin), 2009.04.18
    - Metaphysics of Notation - Eric Ulman (megan), 2009.04.24
    - Ceramics Studio Class (Alex), 2009.04.29
    - Capella Romana (Alvin), 2009.05.03
    - Troika Ranch (Alex), 2009.05.13
    - Cantor Rewired dance (Alvin), 2009.05.17
    - David Eagleman (Alvin), 2009.05.21
    - Guzheng Chinese Music Performance (Alvin), 2009.05.22
    - playsound maker faire 2009 (David), 2009.05.30
    - Duets Project (Alvin), 2009.06.02
    - End Of Year Scrapbook Photos, 2009.06.04
    - SiCa End of Year Celebration (Alvin), 2009.06.04
    - Propositions - devised theater (Alvin), 2009.06.05
    - Beyond My Circle (Uganda) (Michael Rooney), 2009.09.30
    - Beyond My Circle (USA) (Michael Rooney), 2009.09.30
    - Party on the Edge (jason), 2009.10.01
    - POTE (Ethan Yang - no permission), 2009.10.01
    - Jane Sheldon - The Original Cycle (jason), 2009.10.08
    - DJ Olive (Wyatt), 2009.10.15
    - Jump Start (jason), 2009.10.16
    - Cleave (jason), 2009.10.20
    - UNAFF China Doco (Wyatt), 2009.10.21
    - UNAFF (Michael Rooney), 2009.10.25
    - UNAFF Afterparty (Wyatt), 2009.10.25
    - Going to Opera (jason), 2009.10.30
    - W Kamau Bell (Wyatt), 2009.11.02
    - Bullrusher (Michael), 2009.11.03
    - Benedict Anderson (Michael), 2009.11.04
    - Gwyneth Lewis (Wyatt), 2009.11.10
    - Afiara String Quartet (jason), 2009.11.11
    - Light Lab (Michael), 2009.11.11
    - Chocolate Heads (jason), 2009.11.15
    - Gaieties 2009 (Michael), 2009.11.21
    - Social Dance I + II (jason), 2009.11.30
    - Ralph Lemon (Michael), 2009.12.03
    - Choir in memchu (Wyatt), 2009.12.04
    - Design for Exploration (jason), 2009.12.04
  - 2010
    - So Percussion Clap-along (Wyatt), 2010.01.07
    - Steve Reich Art + Invention Speaker Series (jason), 2010.01.07
    - Music and the Brain - Aniruddh Patel (wyatt), 2010.01.12
    - Decasia - Bill Morisson Q+A (Wyatt), 2010.01.19
    - Loren Schoenberg - Jazz Tech Talks (Michael), 2010.01.21
    - Metaphysics of Notation - Bonnie Smith (jason), 2010.01.22
    - Works in progress salon with Dave Douglas and Bill Morrison (jason), 2010.01.22
    - Works in progress salon with Dave Douglas and Bill Morrison (Michael), 2010.01.22
    - Dave Douglas + Band Recording (jason), 2010.01.23
    - Dave Douglas Jazz Master Class (jason), 2010.01.23
    - A+I Speaker Series - LA Theatre Works RFK (Wyatt), 2010.01.26
    - Trans-Poetic Exchange (Michael), 2010.01.29
    - SF Ballet Trainees (jason), 2010.02.04
    - Four Jews on Parnassus (jason), 2010.02.06
    - MATB Mark Tramo (Wyatt), 2010.02.08
    - SF Ballet Backstage Tour (jason), 2010.02.13
    - Aaron Koblin (Wyatt), 2010.02.17
    - Connie Martinez 1stACT (jason), 2010.02.19
    - Stanford Jazz + Dave Douglas (jason), 2010.02.24
    - Pan-Asian Music Festival 2010 Press images, 2010.02
    - Music and the Brain - Petr Janata (Wyatt), 2010.03.01
    - SiCa Ray New York Jazz (Wyatt), 2010.03.03
    - Troubadours Art Ensemble (jason), 2010.03.04
    - Tokai String Quartet (Michael), 2010.03.05
    - Winter Works (jason), 2010.03.05
    - Masters of Latin Jazz (jason), 2010.03.06
    - Taiko Master (jason), 2010.03.25-27
    - Julian Stallabrass (Steve Castillo), 2010.04.07
    - Ann Carlson and Mary Ellen Strom (jason), 2010.04.08
    - Art Affair - Artist Reception (Michael), 2010.04.15
    - Art Affair - CD Release Party (Michael), 2010.04.16
    - Art Affair - Friday (jason), 2010.04.16
    - Art Affair - Saturday (jason), 2010.04.17
    - Art + Invention Student Works Festival (jason), 2010.04.23
    - Art + Invention Student Works Festival (Michael), 2010.04.23
    - Novel+Film Conference (jason), 2010.04.24
    - Concert Hall Ground Breaking (Michael), 2010.05.10
    - Troilus and Cressida (Michael), 2010.05.11
    - Still Life with Decoy (Courtesy of Jason Chuang), 2010.05.27
    - Kinetic Sculpture Class with Reuben Margolin (Dan Tiffany - art dept), 2010.05
    - The Wanderings of Odysseus (Michael), 2010.07.20
    - LSJUMB and ABF in Oregon, 2010.10.1-2
    - Party on the Edge (Jonathan), 2010.10.14
    - Party on the Edge (Michael Silverman), 2010.10.14
    - Party on the Edge (Rooney), 2010.10.14
    - Cathy Horyn + Nancy Troy (Steve Castillo), 2010.10.19
    - Cathy Horn Fashion Writing Wkshp (Jonathan), 2010.10.21
    - Faisal class - mind maps, 2010.11.05
    - Arts Party (Silverman), 2010.11.06
    - All's Well (Rooney), 2010.11.09
    - Arts21 Panel after Screening (Jonathan), 2010.11.10
    - Fusion of Art and Science (Jonathan, 2010.11.11
    - Faisal Class (Jonathan), 2010.11.15
    - Faisal Gallery Reception (Jonathan), 2010.11.15
    - PROOF Play (Silverman), 2010.11.15
    - Wallenberg Exhibit Opening (Jonathan), 2010.11.16
    - Gaities+Band (Jonathan), 2010.11.17
    - Herbert Lachmayer (Silverman), 2010.11.29
    - Cecilia String Quartet, 2010.11
- Press, Series 3
  - "A Case for the Arts at Stanford", 2008 Jan; 1 computer file(s) (PDF)
  - "Engaging the Arts and Creativity", 1 computer file(s) (PDF)
  - Press kit, 7 computer file(s)
  - Celebrating 5 years of the Stanford Arts Initiative, 2011; 1 computer file(s) (PDF)
  - Celebrating 5 Years of the Stanford Arts Initiaitve, 2012 Jan 9; 2.43 megabyte(s) 148 files in 15 directories
- Videorecordings and gallery files, 2008-2010; Series 4; 436 gigabyte(s) (3128 computer files)
  - 2007-2008
    - PlaySound
    - Red Rover
  - 2008-2009
    - arts critics, 2010.01.07
    - cappella, 2010.01.07
    - eurasia, 2010.01.22
    - futurism, 2010.01.23
    - guzheng, 2010.01.26
    - Love's Labors Lost, 2010.02.06
    - matb09, 2010.02.17
    - metaphysics of notation, 2010.02
    - Misha Dichter, 2010.03.01
    - novel, 2010.03.05
    - PAMF2009, 2010.03.06
    - peter and the wolf, 2010.04.08
    - photos, 2010.05.11
    - Reactions to the Record, 2010.05.27
    - Rocco di Pietro, 2010.07.20
    - Songwriter's Workshop, 2010.11.05
    - studentarts, 2010.11.11
    - video
    - Yoko Ono
    - Yoko Tawada
  - 2009-2010
    - 26_March_ Four Jews on Parnassus (a+i)
    - 26_March_Aaron Koblin SiCa Presents (a+i)
    - 26_March_Connie Martinez SiCa Presents
    - 26_March_DonaldKnuth (a+i)
    - 26_March_Julie Ralph (a+i)
    - 26_March_MATB Tramo (a+i)
    - 26_March_Transpoetic Exchange (a+i)
    - 27_April_ Stanford Jazz Orchestra with Dave Douglas
    - 27_April_Masters of Latin Jazz Concert (SALJE)
    - 27_April_MATB Janata (a+i)
    - 27_April_Richard Powers (a+i)
    - 27_April_Tokai String Quartet
    - 27_April_Troubadors Art Ensemble
    - 27_April_Winter Works Dance Concert (a+i)
    - 30_May_Art + Invention Grant Projects (a+i)
    - 30_May_Julian Stallabrass
    - 30_May_Taiko Master Residency
    - 30_May_Trimpin (a+i)
    - 31_June_ Dave Douglas recording documentary (a+i)
    - 31_June_Ann Carlson (a+i)
    - 31_June_Art Affair
    - 31_June_Concert Hall Groundbreaking
    - 31_June_Latin Jazz concert
    - 31_June_Laurie Anderson (a+i)
    - 31_June_Troilus&Cressida
    - 32_July_Graphic Novel feature (a+i)
    - 32_July_Reuben Margolin (a+i)
    - 32_July_Student Works Festival (a+i)
    - 33_Aug_SLSQ Seminar
    - 33_Aug_Soda Fountain
    - 33_Aug_Summer Theater
  - 2010-2011
    - 1_Nov_CathyHoryn Salon
    - 1_Nov_Concert Hall SLSQ performance
    - 1_Nov_Victor Gama Concert
    - 2_Dec_Alls Well That Ends Well
    - 2_Dec_Annie Cohen-Solal
    - 2_Dec_Harry Elam talk
    - 2_Dec_POTE 2010
    - 3_Jan_Faisal feature
    - 3_Jan_Gallery160 opening
    - 3_Jan_Gama-Trimpin Interview
    - 4_Art21 Kentridge panel
- Website, 2010 Dec 9; Series 5; 193 gigabyte(s) (6461 computer files)
  Captured via HTTrack, 2010 Dec 9.